Finding Aid for United Church of Christ. Michigan Conference records, 1840-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Evangelical and Reformed Church (Box 7)
  The Evangelical and Reformed Church series (1.5 linear feet) contains minutes of the Fort Wayne Classis Evangelical and Reformed Church. It also contains newsletters and acts/proceedings of the Michigan-Indiana Synod of the Evangelical and Reformed Church. The series includes information from the following women's organizations: Ann Arbor Regional Women's Guild, Michigan-Indiana Synodical Women's Guild, and the Women's Guild of the Evangelical and Reformed Church. Each section contains items such as meeting minutes, newsletters, by-laws, and annual reports. The Michigan-Indiana Synodical Women's Guild section also contains directories between the years of 1942-1958. The miscellaneous folder in the Women's Guild of the Evangelical and Reformed Church contains reports, a photograph, meeting minutes, and correspondence.
  - Minutes of the Fort Wayne (Indiana) Classis Evangelical and Reformed church, 1931-1940 (Box 7)
  - Acts and Proceedings of the Michigan-Indiana Synod of the Evangelical and Reformed Church, 1944-1963 (Box 7)
  - Synod News [newsletter of the Michigan-Indiana Synod of the Evangelical and Reformed Church], 1956-1962 (Box 7)
  - Evangelical and Reformed Church printed material (Box 7)
  - Ann Arbor Regional Women's Guild (name of the organization varies)
    - Annual reports, 1951-1962 (Box 8)
    - By-laws and constitution (Box 8)
    - Covenant Association
      - Minutes, 1981-1986; 2 folders (Box 8)
      - Newsletters, 1976-1984 (scattered) (Box 8)
    - Minutes, 1928-1965; 4 folders (Box 8)
    - Meeting charts, 1939-1986 (Box 8)
    - Officers, 1982-1989 (Box 8)
    - Programs, 1940-1976 (Box 8)
  - Michigan-Indiana Synodical Women's Guild
    - By-laws and constitution (Box 8)
    - Conference, May 19, 1964 (Box 8)
    - Conventions, 1942-1964; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Directories, 1942-1958 (Box 8)
    - Minutes, 1940-1964; 4 folders (Box 8)
    - Newsletters and Directories, 1943-1958 (Box 8)
  - Women's Guild of the Evangelical and Reformed Church (United Church of Christ)
    - General Meeting minutes, 1941-1960 (scattered) (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8)
- Church files
  The Church files series (4.5 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically by city and are primarily Congregational. These records concern the establishment of churches in these cities and contain items such as correspondence and minutes. They may be files about the churches that were held by the United Church of Christ Michigan Conference, rather than by the churches themselves.
  - Alamo (Box 9)
  - Allegan, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Allenville, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Almont (Box 9)
  - Alpena (Box 9)
  - Alton (Box 9)
  - Ann Arbor, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Armada (Box 9)
  - Athens (Box 9)
  - Augusta (Box 9)
  - Bachelor (Box 9)
  - Bancroft (Box 9)
  - Baroda (Box 9)
  - Battle Creek, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Bay Mills (Box 9)
  - Bedford (Box 9)
  - Belford (Box 9)
  - Benton Harbor (Box 9)
  - Benzonia (Box 9)
  - Big Prairie (Box 9)
  - Birmingham, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Bradley (Box 9)
  - Branch (Box 9)
  - Breckenridge (Box 9)
  - Bridgeport (Box 9)
  - Bridgeman (Box 9)
  - Bronson (Box 9)
  - Buckley (Box 9)
  - Butternut, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Cadillac (Box 9)
  - Calumet (Box 9)
  - Cannonsburg, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Carson City (Box 9)
  - Cassopolis (Box 9)
  - Central Lake (Box 9)
  - Charlotte (Box 9)
  - Chase (Box 9)
  - Chassell (Box 9)
  - Cheboygan (Box 9)
  - Chelsea First Congregational Church (Box 9)
  - Chelsea St. Paul's Church (Box 9)
  - Chester Station (Box 9)
  - Chippewa (Box 9)
  - Clarksville, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Clawson (Box 9)
  - Clinton (Box 9)
  - Coloma (Box 10)
  - Conklin (Box 10)
  - Constantine (Box 10)
  - Cooper (Box 10)
  - Coral (Box 10)
  - Covert (Box 10)
  - Crystal (Box 10)
  - Custer, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Dearborn, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Dearborn St. James Evangelical and Reformed Church (Box 10)
  - Delta County (Box 10)
  - Detroit. Boulevard Congregational Church (Box 10)
  - Detroit. Bushnell Congregational Church (Box 10)
  - Detroit. Melvindale Congregational Church (Box 10)
  - Detroit. Central Congregational Church (Box 10)
  - Detroit. First Congregational Church (Box 10)
  - Detroit. Mayflower Congregational Church (Box 10)
  - Detroit. Mount Hope Congregational Church (Box 10)
  - Detroit. North Congregational Church (Box 10)
  - Detroit. Peace United Church of Christ Evangelical and Reformed (Box 10)
  - Detroit. St. John's Evangelical and Reformed Church (Box 10)
  - Detroit. Trinity Evangelical Church (Box 10)
  - Detroit. Miscellaneous material (Box 10)
  - Dexter. First Congregational, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Dexter. St. Andrews United Church of Christ, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Dowagiac (Box 10)
  - Dundee, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - East Paisonville (Box 10)
  - Eau Claire (Box 10)
  - Eden, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Ellsworth (Box 10)
  - Elsie (Box 10)
  - Farmington. Salem United Church of Christ (Box 10)
  - Fenwick (Box 10)
  - Flint. Congregational-Unitarian Church, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Flint. Cross Congregational Church (Box 10)
  - Flint. Baptist Church (Box 10)
  - Fountain (Box 10)
  - Freda (Box 10)
  - Fredonia (Box 10)
  - Freeland (Box 10)
  - Fulton. Evangelical and Reformed Church (Box 10)
  - Gibraltar (Box 10)
  - Gilmare (Box 10)
  - Grand Blanc (Box 10)
  - Grand Haven (Box 10)
  - Grand Junction (Box 10)
  - Grand Rapids. Burlingame Congregational Church (Box 11)
  - Grand Rapids. Park Congregational Church, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Grand Rapids. Mayflower Congregational Church. (Box 11)
  - Grand Rapids. Trinity Congregational Church (Box 11)
  - Grandville (Box 11)
  - Greenville, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Grosse Pointe. Grace United Church of Christ (Box 11)
  - Hancock (Box 11)
  - Hartford, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Hersey (Box 11)
  - Highland (Box 11)
  - Highland Park, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Hillsdale County Parish (Box 11)
  - Hopkins, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Hopkinsburg (Box 11)
  - Howard City, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Hubbell (Box 11)
  - Hudson (Box 11)
  - Hudsonville (Box 11)
  - Jackson. Arbor Grove (Box 11)
  - Jackson. First Congregational Church (Box 11)
  - Jackson. Holy Trinity (Box 11)
  - Jackson. Sandstone Congregational Church (Box 11)
  - Jackson. South Jackson Community Church (Box 11)
  - Johannesburg, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Kaleva (Box 12)
  - Kendall (Box 12)
  - Kinderhook, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Lansing. Pilgrim Congregational Church (Box 12)
  - Lansing. Plymouth Congregational Church (Box 12)
  - Lawrence (Box 12)
  - Leonidas (Box 12)
  - Litchfield (Box 12)
  - Livonia. Nativity United Church of Christ (Box 12)
  - Livonia. Pilgrim Congregational Church (Box 12)
  - Madison, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Mancelona (Box 12)
  - Marshall (Box 12)
  - Maybee (Box 12)
  - Metamara (Box 12)
  - Moline (Box 12)
  - Muskegon, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Nankin (Box 12)
  - Nevins Lake (Box 12)
  - Newark (Box 12)
  - New Haven (Box 12)
  - North Adams (Box 12)
  - Omena (Box 12)
  - Perry (Box 12)
  - Pine Grove (Box 12)
  - Pleasanton (Box 12)
  - Pontiac (Box 12)
  - Port Huron (Box 12)
  - Port Sanilac (Box 12)
  - Pullman, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Ransom (Box 12)
  - Red Jacket (Box 12)
  - Redridge (Box 12)
  - Reed City (Box 12)
  - Richmond (Box 12)
  - Rochester (Box 12)
  - Rockwood (Box 12)
  - Romeo (Box 12)
  - Rondo (Box 12)
  - Roscommon (Box 13)
  - Rosedale (Box 13)
  - Royal Oak. Emmanuel-Bethel United Church of Christ (Box 13)
  - St. Clair (Box 13)
  - Saginaw (Box 13)
  - Saugatuck, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Shaftsburg (Box 13)
  - Sheridan (Box 13)
  - Sister Lakes (Box 13)
  - Somerset (Box 13)
  - South Boston (Box 13)
  - South Jefferson (Box 13)
  - Stanton Texas (Box 13)
  - Topinabee (Box 13)
  - Traverse City (Box 13)
  - Union City (Box 13)
  - Utica (Box 13)
  - Vanderbilt (Box 13)
  - Vicksburg (Box 13)
  - Victor, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Watervliet, Plymouth Congregational Church (Box 13)
  - Watervliet, St. Paul's United Church of Christ (Box 13)
  - Willow Run Village (Box 13)
- Photographs
  The Photographs, 1890s-1900s series (0.5 linear feet) contains photos of various Congregational church buildings, parsonages, and homes, many from Upper Peninsula communities in the period of 1890s and 1900s. There are also photographs and portraits (1930s-1950s) of Congregational Church ministers.
  - Brimley (near) and Drummond Island (Box 13)
  - Ensign and Ewen (Box 13)
  - Grand Rapids (Box 13)
  - Iroquois and Jackson (Box 13)
  - Ministers (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous, including Kalamazoo (Box 13)
  - Sugar Island (Box 13)
  - Trout Creek, Vienna, and unidentified (Box 13)
- Ministerial files
  The Ministerial files series (4.5 linear feet) is arranged alphabetically by clergyman. The clergymen were either pastors of Congregational or Evangelical and Reformed churches which later joined the Michigan Conference of the United Church of Christ, or pastors of churches which refused to merge into the Michigan Conference. The files contain biographical information and correspondence between the Conference and the individual pastors.
  - A-D (Box 14)
  - D-H (Box 15)
  - I-L (Box 16)
  - M-S (Box 17)
  - S-Y (Box 18)
  - Obituaries of pastors and others, 1968-1974 (Box 18)
- Student ministry
  The Student ministry series (0.5 linear feet) includes information on student ministries in cities across Michigan. The bulk of the files contain correspondence and reports concerning student affairs during the 1940s and 1950s. Finally, the series contains a description of the University of Michigan's North Campus Development project and correspondence.
  - Colleges and seminaries (Box 18)
  - Student work
    - Ann Arbor (Box 18)
    - Big Rapids. Ferris Institute (Box 18)
    - East Lansing (Box 18)
    - Kalamazoo (Box 18)
    - Olivet (Box 18)
    - Ypsilanti (Box 18)
  - Ann Arbor-North Campus Development (Box 18)